Guide to the Benét family papers, 1918-1960
Benét family papers, 1918-1960
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Benét Family Papers, 1918-1960
4667
Benét family
.6 cubic ft.
Manuscripts, correspondence, bibliographies, publishing releases, proofs, scripts, photographs, sheet music, subject files.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Manuscripts, correspondence, bibliographies, publishing releases and proofs, scripts, photographs, sheet music, subject files, and other miscellaneous papers of Stephen Vincent Benét, Laura Benét, and William Rose Benét.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Manuscripts, correspondence, bibliographies, publishing releases and proofs, scripts, photographs, sheet music, subject files, and other miscellaneous papers of Stephen Vincent Benét, Laura Benét, and William Rose Benét.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Benet family.; Benet, Stephen Vincent,--1898-1943.; Benet, Laura.; Benet, William Rose,--1886-1950.
Occupations:
Authors--United States.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Stephen Vincent Benét papers
Box 1
Series II. William Rose Benét papers
Box 1
Series III. Laura Benét
Box 2
Series IV. Photographs
Box 1
Series V. Miscellaneous
Council for Democracy
Box 3
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Stephen Vincent Benét [SVB] papers
  - Stephen Vincent Benét: "The Minotaur," unpublished manuscript; letters to Mr. Braithwaite re: manuscript, 1918 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Stephen Vincent Benét: "Nightmare for Future Reference," manuscript, typescript, ca. 1940 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Stephen Vincent Benét: Selected bibliography (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Stephen Vincent Benét: Bibliographical information; correspondence; biographical information, 1939-1954 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Stephen Vincent Benét: "The Ballad of the Duke's Mercy," typescript., c. 1939 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Stephen Vincent Benét: Correspondence with George Abbe, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Stephen Vincent Benét: American Academy of Arts and Letters Ceremonial; remarks; correspondence, address; "The Prayer" manuscript, a poem about arthritis; poem by Laura Benét re: SVB, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Stephen Vincent Benét: Correspondence; manuscript of poem to Walter Damrasch; typescript copies of New York Times articles, 1941-1949 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Stephen Vincent Benét: Publishing releases; poems; letter to H.C. Baird, 1856; obituaries of Mrs. Frances Benét, 1933-1940 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Stephen Vincent Benét: "Service Time - It's Maritime," typescript of radio play, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Series II. William Rose Benét [WRB] papers
  - William Rose Benét: Poem, "S.V.B. 1898-1943"; correspondence to Eugene Delafield, 1938-1944; correspondence to Mr. Wilder from the Algonquin Hotel, 1960; to Basil Davenport, 1938, 1941, 1938-44, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - William Rose Benét: "The Seventh Pawn," typescript, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - William Rose Benét: Correspondence, 1914-1948 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - William Rose Benét: "The Blackamoor's Pantomime," typescript, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Series III. Laura Benét [LB]
  - Laura Benét: poems, 1948, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Laura Benét: copyreaders of essays on American poets, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 2-4)
  - Laura Benét: Radio broadcast scripts, 1940-54 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Laura Benét: "The Eternal Light," radio scripts, 1944-45 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Series IV. Photographs
  - Photographs: Stephen Vincent Benét; SVB and Raymond Massey; SVB and Rosemary, 1941, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Photographs: Laura Benét; Stephen Vincent Benét; SVB and ?, 1850-1914 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Series V. Miscellaneous
  - Political and miscellaneous correspondence, newsclippings, 1941-53 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - National Institute of Arts and Letters, 1936-50; Bulletins, nominations and ballots, programs, letters, addresses (Box 3, Folder 2-3)
  - Political and literary miscellany, 1929-51; Bulletins, reports, music, graduate paper (Box 3, Folder 4-7)
  - Council for Democracy
    - Council for Democracy: Minutes of Special Meeting of the Board of Directors, Oct. 20, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Council for Democracy: Minutes of Special Meeting of the Board of Directors, Dec. 15, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Council for Democracy: Minutes of Special Meeting of the Board of Directors, Jan. 5, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Council for Democracy: A Digest of Proceedings - the Negro Press Conference, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Council for Democracy: Miscellany, 1942-44; Bulletins, scripts, minutes, statements, reports, newsletters (Box 3, Folder 12-13)